A Guide to the Rockefeller Sanitary Commission for the Eradication of Hookworm Disease records FA057
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Sanitary Commission for the Eradication of Hookworm Disease records
1903-1915
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Sanitary Commission for the Eradication of Hookworm Disease
FA057
7.73 Cubic Feet 15 document boxes, 11 microfilm reels, 5 bound volumes.
Arrangement note
The Rockefeller Sanitary Commission records are arranged in four series.
Series 1 - Administration
Series 2 - Field Offices
Series 3 - Minutes and Reports
Series 4 - Financial Records
Series 5 - Rockefeller Sanitary Commission Annual Reports
Biographical/Historical note
The Rockefeller Sanitary Commission for the Eradication of Hookworm Disease was organized on October 26, 1909, as a result of a gift of $1,000,000.00 from John D. Rockefeller, Sr. Mr. Rockefeller hoped that a five-year campaign against the disease would lead to the "adoption of well-considered plans for a cooperative movement of the Medical Profession, Public Health Officials, Board of Trade, Churches, Schools, the Press, and other agencies... ." The gift was accepted on October 26, 1909, by William Welch, Simon Flexner, Charles W. Stiles, Edwin Alderman, David Houston, P. P. Claxton, J. Y. Joyner, Walter H. Page, H. B. Frissell, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Frederick T. Gates, and Starr Murphy.
The bylaws use the wording of Mr. Rockefeller's letter of gift in their objectives towards the cure and prevention of hookworm disease. It was to be a joint effort between the states and the Sanitary Commission. The Commission was to furnish the initial impetus and to serve as an information agency for the states. It also paid the salaries of the field personnel. Offices were opened in Washington in January, 1910, and the business of organization began. The state was the basic unit of work and the state public health system was the main contact, though medical associations, public school systems, and the press were enlisted. Each state created a Director of Sanitation who was appointed jointly by the Sanitary Commission and the state public health authorities. The Director of Sanitation was a state official, responsible for directing and organizing the campaign in their own state. Sanitary inspectors were under the province of the State Director of Sanitation. These, together with the microscopists, were the field staff. They surveyed the state to determine areas and degrees of infection, enlisted the aid of local community members in securing appropriations to add to those of the Sanitary Commission, worked with local physicians, gave treatment to the infected, inspected schools, and gave lectures and demonstrations to instruct people on how to prevent reinfection and avoid soil pollution. This last effort of lectures and demonstrations included the press and the local education systems, as well as all the community groups that could be interested in the project. Particular attention was paid to the instruction of school children. Education was considered as large a part of the campaign as was treatment. In 1910, Virginia, North Carolina, Georgia, South Carolina, Tennessee, Arkansas, Mississippi, Alabama, and Louisiana all began hookworm campaigns. By 1914, Kentucky and Texas had established their programs, and preliminary surveys had been taken in several other states. Dispensary work, instruction in medical and public schools, and intensive community work all increased public awareness of hookworm as a disease, and the possibility of its cure and prevention. The campaign ended formally in 1914, though some of the programs carried over until June, 1915.
Related Archival Materials note
See also: FA324 Office of the Messrs Rockefeller records, Rockefeller Boards, Series O
Conditions Governing Access
The archival material has been reformatted. Access to the original paper records is restricted. Microfilm user copies are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Rockefeller Sanitary Commission records were received by the Rockefeller Foundation Archives in 1969.
Scope and Contents
The Rockefeller Sanitary Commission records date from 1909 to 1915. The subjects documented in these records include: dispensaries, health education, health inspection, health law and legislation, hookworm disease and treatment, philanthropy, public health planning, sanitary engineering, and state health systems.
Among the correspondents are: Baily Ashford, M. H. Boerner, E. V. Caldwell, D. P. Curry, William Dinsmore, John Ferrell, A. G. Fort, Allen Freeman, C. W. Garrison, Frederick T. Gates, Jerome D. Greene, C. A. Grote, W. P. Jacocks, W. S. Leathers, A. J. Lock, A. T. McCormick, L. G. Myers, Starr Murphy, Sidney Porter, Wickliffe Rose, Morgan Smith, C. W. Stiles, J. La Bruce Ward, B. E. Washburn, and Olin West.
The Rockefeller Sanitary Commission records are not complete. Important material on the organization, policies, and termination of the Commission may be found in the Rockefeller Family Archives, Record Group 2 - Office of the Messrs Rockefeller, Series O - Rockefeller Boards, located at the Rockefeller Archive Center.
Diseases; Hospitals -- Administration; Public policy; Sanitary engineering; Health education; Philanthropy; Hookworm disease; Public health; Health systems agencies; Hospitals
- Administration, 1903-1939; 1; 1.17 Cubic Feet 2 microfilm boxes (35mm) and 3 letter document boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains material which documents the administration of the Commission's Washington Office, routine requests for information, personnel files, information on mailing cases, conferences, history, general hookworm statistics, and some policy descriptions.
  Arrangement note
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  - Alpha Photo Engraving Company, 1913-1914 (Reel M 01, Frame 1, Box 1, Folder 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    The archival material has been reformatted. Access to the original paper records is restricted. Microfilm user copies are available for access.
  - American Academy of Political Science, 1911 (Reel M 01, Frame 2, Box 1, Folder 2)
    Biographical / Historical
  - "American Magazine", 1912 (Reel M 01, Frame 3, Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Medical Association, 1913-1914 (Reel M 01, Frame 4, Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Medical Association, 1913-1914 (Reel M 01, Frame 5, Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Press Association, 1912-1914 (Reel M 01, Frame 6, Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Public Health Association, 1910-1913 (Reel M 01, Frame 7, Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Red Cross Town & County Nursing Service, 1912-1914 (Reel M 01, Frame 8, Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American School Hygiene Association, 1911-1913 (Reel M 01, Frame 9, Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Anderson, G. K., 1913 (Reel M 01, Frame 10, Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Arnold, W. F., 1910-1911 (Reel M 01, Frame 11, Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bausch and Lomb Optical, 1914 (Reel M 01, Frame 12, Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bourland, A. P., 1914 (Reel M 01, Frame 13, Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Brownlow, Louis, 1913 (Reel M 01, Frame 14, Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bureau of Municipal Research, 1911-1912 (Reel M 01, Frame 15, Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Buttrick, Wallace, 1914 (Reel M 01, Frame 16, Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Colbert, G. W., 1911 (Reel M 01, Frame 17, Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Little Rock Conference", 1913 (Reel M 01, Frame 18, Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "Second Annual Hookworm Conference", 1911 (Reel M 01, Frame 19, Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Crook, Jere L., 1910 (Reel M 01, Frame 20, Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Eliot, Charles, 1914 (Reel M 01, Frame 21, Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Equitable Life Insurance, 1910-1911 (Reel M 01, Frame 22, Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Eves, S. A., 1913 (Reel M 01, Frame 23, Box 1, Folder 23)
  - "Farm and Fireside", 1910 (Reel M 01, Frame 24, Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America, 1911-1913 (Reel M 01, Frame 25, Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Ferrell, John A., 1913-1915 (Reel M 01, Frame 26, Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Flexner, Simon, 1909-1915 (Reel M 01, Frame 27, Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Gates, Frederick T., 1909-1915 (Reel M 01, Frame 28, Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Gates, Frederick T., 1909-1915 (Reel M 01, Frame 29, Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Greene, Jerome D., 1912-1915 (Reel M 01, Frame 30, Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Gregory, Emily, 1913 (Reel M 01, Frame 31, Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Heydt, Charles, 1914 (Reel M 01, Frame 32, Box 2, Folder 32)
  - History, 1910-1914, 1938-1939 (Reel M 01, Frame 33, Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Hookworm Statistics, circa 1903-1909 (Reel M 01, Frame 34, Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Hookworm - Miscellaneous, 1911, 1913, n.d. (Reel M 01, Frame 35, Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Houghton-Mifflin Company, 1913 (Reel M 01, Frame 36, Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Hughes, T. E., 1914 (Reel M 01, Frame 37, Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Hutchinson, Woods, 1910 (Reel M 01, Frame 38, Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Improved Mailing Case Company, 1910-1914 (Reel M 01, Frame 39, Box 2, Folder 39)
  - International Congress on Hygiene and Demography, 1912 (Reel M 01, Frame 40, Box 2, Folder 40)
  - "International Who's Who", 1911 (Reel M 01, Frame 41, Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Johnson, B. F., 1910 (Reel M 01, Frame 42, Box 2, Folder 42)
  - "Journal of the American Medical Association", 1911-1914 (Reel M 01, Frame 43, Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Kaustine Company, 1914 (Reel M 01, Frame 44, Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Lund, Wallace, 1914 (Reel M 01, Frame 45, Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Elizabeth McCormick Memorial Fund, 1913 (Reel M 02, Frame 1, Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Murphy, Edgar G., 1910-1911 (Reel M 02, Frame 2, Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Murphy, Starr, 1909-1915 (Reel M 02, Frame 3, Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Myers, L. G., 1910-1915 (Reel M 02, Frame 4, Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Myers, L. G., 1910-1915 (Reel M 02, Frame 5, Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Myers Manufacturing Company, 1913-1914 (Reel M 02, Frame 6, Box 2, Folder 51)
  - National Association for the Study and Prevention of Tuberculosis, 1910 (Reel M 02, Frame 7, Box 2, Folder 52)
  - National Conference of Charities and Correction, 1911-1914 (Reel M 02, Frame 8, Box 2, Folder 53)
  - National Conservation Association, 1911-1912 (Reel M 02, Frame 9, Box 2, Folder 54)
  - "National Cyclopedia of American Biography", 1915 (Reel M 02, Frame 10, Box 3, Folder 55)
  - "National Drainage Congress", 1913 (Reel M 02, Frame 11, Box 3, Folder 56)
  - National Medical Association, 1911 (Reel M 02, Frame 12, Box 3, Folder 57)
  - North Carolina Child Labor Committee, 1914 (Reel M 02, Frame 13, Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Outlook Company, 1913 (Reel M 02, Frame 14, Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Pan American Union, 1911-1913 (Reel M 02, Frame 15, Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Parke, Davis & Company, 1911-1914 (Reel M 02, Frame 16, Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Peabody College for Teachers, 1914 (Reel M 02, Frame 17, Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Page, Arthur, 1910-1913 (Reel M 02, Frame 18, Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Page, Walter, 1910-1914 (Reel M 02, Frame 19, Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Page, Walter, 1910-1914 (Reel M 02, Frame 20, Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Personnel Records, 1939 (Reel M 02, Frame 21, Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Requests for Information, 1910-1915 (Reel M 02, Frame 22, Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 1909-1914 (Reel M 02, Frame 23, Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1914 (Reel M 02, Frame 24, Box 3, Folder 69)
  - State Boards of Health, 1910-1912 (Reel M 02, Frame 25, Box 3, Folder 70)
  - State Directors, 1910-1911 (Reel M 02, Frame 26, Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Stiles, Charles W., 1910-1915 (Reel M 02, Frame 27, Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Stiles, Charles W., 1910-1915 (Reel M 02, Frame 28, Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Stiles, Charles W., 1910-1915 (Reel M 02, Frame 29, Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Stiles, Charles W., 1910-1915 (Reel M 02, Frame 30, Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Stiles, Charles W., 1910-1915 (Reel M 02, Frame 31, Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Stiles, Charles W. - Reports, 1910, 1913 (Reel M 02, Frame 32, Box 3, Folder 77)
- Field Offices, 1909-1915; 2; 3.89 Cubic Feet 7 microfilm boxes (35mm) and 10 letter document boxes
  This series comprises the bulk of the records. Material in this series includes state directors' reports, field staff correspondence, and all correspondence documenting a particular state.
  Material in this series is arranged alphabetically by state.
  - Alabama
    Alabama
    - Alabama - General, 1910-1911 (Reel M 03, Frame 1, Box 4, Folder 78)
    - Alabama - General, 1910-1911 (Reel M 03, Frame 1, Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Alabama - Reports, circa 1911-1913 (Reel M 03, Frame 3, Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Alabama - Clippings, circa 1911-1914 (Reel M 03, Frame 4, Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Alaska
    Alaska
    - Alaska, 1911 (Reel M 03, Frame 5, Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Arizona
    Arizona
    - Arizona, 1910 (Reel M 03, Frame 6, Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Arkansas
    Arkansas
    - Arkansas - General, 1910-1915 (Reel M 03, Frame 7, Box 4, Folder 84)
    - Arkansas - General, 1910-1915 (Reel M 03, Frame 8, Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Arkansas - General, 1910-1915 (Reel M 03, Frame 9, Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Arkansas - General, 1910-1915 (Reel M 03, Frame 10, Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Arkansas - General, 1910-1915 (Reel M 03, Frame 11, Box 4, Folder 88)
    - Arkansas - General, 1910-1915 (Reel M 03, Frame 12, Box 4, Folder 89)
    - Arkansas - Reports, 1911, 1913, 1914 (Reel M 03, Frame 13, Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Arkansas - Clippings, circa 1913-1914 (Reel M 03, Frame 14, Box 4, Folder 91)
  - California
    California
    - California, 1910-1914 (Reel M 03, Frame 15, Box 5, Folder 92)
  - Colorado
    Colorado
    - Colorado, 1914 (Reel M 03, Frame 16, Box 5, Folder 93)
  - Florida
    Florida
    - Florida, 1910-1915 (Reel M 03, Frame 17, Box 5, Folder 94)
  - Georgia
    Georgia
    - Georgia - General, 1910-1915 (Reel M 04, Frame 1, Box 5, Folder 95)
    - Georgia - General, 1910-1915 (Reel M 04, Frame 2, Box 5, Folder 96)
    - Georgia - General, 1910-1915 (Reel M 04, Frame 3, Box 5, Folder 97)
    - Georgia - General, 1910-1915 (Reel M 04, Frame 4, Box 5, Folder 98)
    - Georgia - General, 1910-1915 (Reel M 04, Frame 5, Box 5, Folder 99)
    - Georgia - General, 1910-1915 (Reel M 04, Frame 6, Box 5, Folder 100)
    - Georgia - General, 1910-1915 (Reel M 04, Frame 7, Box 5, Folder 101)
    - Georgia - General, 1910-1915 (Reel M 04, Frame 8, Box 5, Folder 102)
    - Georgia - General, 1910-1915 (Reel M 04, Frame 9, Box 5, Folder 103)
    - Georgia - Reports, 1911-1913 (Reel M 04, Frame 10, Box 5, Folder 104)
    - Georgia - Reports, 1911-1913 (Reel M 04, Frame 11, Box 5, Folder 105)
    - Georgia - Reports, 1914 (Reel M 04, Frame 12, Box 6, Folder 106)
    - Georgia - Reports - Miscellaneous, 1913 (Reel M 04, Frame 13, Box 6, Folder 107)
  - Hawaii
    Hawaii
    - Hawaii, 1911 (Reel M 04, Frame 14, Box 6, Folder 108)
  - Idaho
    Idaho
    - Idaho, 1910 (Reel M 04, Frame 15, Box 6, Folder 109)
  - Illinois
    Illinois
    - Illinois, 1914 (Reel M 04, Frame 16, Box 6, Folder 110)
  - Indiana
    Indiana
    - Indiana, 1912-1914 (Reel M 04, Frame 17, Box 6, Folder 111)
  - Kansas
    Kansas
    - Kansas, 1910-1913 (Reel M 05, Frame 1, Box 6, Folder 112)
  - Kentucky
    Kentucky
    - Kentucky, 1910-1915 (Reel M 05, Frame 2, Box 6, Folder 113)
    - Kentucky, 1910-1915 (Reel M 05, Frame 3, Box 6, Folder 114)
    - Kentucky, 1910-1915 (Reel M 05, Frame 4, Box 6, Folder 115)
    - Kentucky, 1910-1915 (Reel M 05, Frame 5, Box 6, Folder 116)
    - Kentucky, 1910-1915 (Reel M 05, Frame 6, Box 6, Folder 117)
    - Kentucky, 1910-1915 (Reel M 05, Frame 7, Box 6, Folder 118)
    - Kentucky, 1910-1915 (Reel M 05, Frame 8, Box 6, Folder 119)
    - Kentucky, 1910-1915 (Reel M 05, Frame 9, Box 6, Folder 120)
  - Louisiana
    Louisiana
    - Louisiana - General, 1910 (Reel M 05, Frame 10, Box 6, Folder 121)
    - Louisiana - General, 1911-1915 (Reel M 05, Frame 11, Box 7, Folder 122)
    - Louisiana - General, 1911-1915 (Reel M 05, Frame 12, Box 7, Folder 123)
    - Louisiana - General, 1911-1915 (Reel M 05, Frame 13, Box 7, Folder 124)
    - Louisiana - General, 1911-1915 (Reel M 05, Frame 14, Box 7, Folder 125)
    - Louisiana - General, 1911-1915 (Reel M 05, Frame 15, Box 7, Folder 126)
    - Louisiana - Reports, 1911-1914 (Reel M 05, Frame 16, Box 7, Folder 127)
  - Maine
    Maine
    - Maine, 1910 (Reel M 06, Frame 1, Box 7, Folder 128)
  - Maryland
    Maryland
    - Maryland, 1910-1913 (Reel M 06, Frame 2, Box 7, Folder 129)
  - Mississippi
    Mississippi
    - Mississippi - General, 1909-June 1911 (Reel M 06, Frame 3, Box 7, Folder 130)
    - Mississippi - General, 1909-June 1911 (Reel M 06, Frame 4, Box 7, Folder 131)
    - Mississippi - General, 1909-June 1911 (Reel M 06, Frame 5, Box 7, Folder 132)
    - Mississippi - General, July 1911-1915 (Reel M 06, Frame 6, Box 8, Folder 133)
    - Mississippi - General, July 1911-1915 (Reel M 06, Frame 7, Box 8, Folder 134)
    - Mississippi - General, July 1911-1915 (Reel M 06, Frame 8, Box 8, Folder 135)
    - Mississippi - General, July 1911-1915 (Reel M 06, Frame 9, Box 8, Folder 136)
    - Mississippi - General, July 1911-1915 (Reel M 06, Frame 10, Box 8, Folder 137)
    - Mississippi - Reports, circa 1911-1914 (Reel M 06, Frame 11, Box 8, Folder 138)
  - Nevada
    Nevada
    - Nevada, 1914 (Reel M 06, Frame 12, Box 8, Folder 139)
  - New Jersey
    New Jersey
    - New Jersey, 1910 (Reel M 06, Frame 13, Box 8, Folder 140)
  - North Carolina
    North Carolina
    - North Carolina - General, 1910-June 1911 (Reel M 06, Frame 14, Box 8, Folder 141)
    - North Carolina - General, 1910-June 1911 (Reel M 06, Frame 15, Box 8, Folder 142)
    - North Carolina - General, 1910-June 1911 (Reel M 06, Frame 16, Box 8, Folder 143)
    - North Carolina - General, July 1911-1915 (Reel M 07, Frame 1, Box 9, Folder 144)
    - North Carolina - General, July 1911-1915 (Reel M 07, Frame 2, Box 9, Folder 145)
    - North Carolina - General, July 1911-1915 (Reel M 07, Frame 3, Box 9, Folder 146)
    - North Carolina - General, July 1911-1915 (Reel M 07, Frame 4, Box 9, Folder 147)
    - North Carolina - General, July 1911-1915 (Reel M 07, Frame 5, Box 9, Folder 148)
    - North Carolina - General, July 1911-1915 (Reel M 07, Frame 6, Box 9, Folder 149)
    - North Carolina - General, July 1911-1915 (Reel M 07, Frame 7, Box 9, Folder 150)
    - North Carolina - Reports, 1910-1914 (Reel M 07, Frame 8, Box 9, Folder 151)
    - North Carolina - Reports, 1910-1914 (Reel M 07, Frame 9, Box 9, Folder 152)
    - North Carolina - Community Health Reports, 1914-1915 (Reel M 07, Frame 10, Box 10, Folder 153)
    - North Carolina - Community Health Reports, 1914-1915 (Reel M 07, Frame 11, Box 10, Folder 154)
    - North Carolina - Community Health Reports, 1914-1915 (Reel M 07, Frame 12, Box 10, Folder 155)
    - Knotts Island, North Carolina, 1913-1914 (Reel M 07, Frame 13, Box 10, Folder 156)
  - Ohio
    Ohio
    - Ohio, 1910-1912 (Reel M 07, Frame 14, Box 10, Folder 157)
  - Oklahoma
    Oklahoma
    - Oklahoma - General, 1910-1914 (Reel M 07, Frame 15, Box 10, Folder 158)
    - Oklahoma - Reports, 1914 (Reel M 07, Frame 16, Box 10, Folder 159)
  - Philippines
    Philippines
    - Philippine Islands, 1911-1914 (Reel M 07, Frame 17, Box 10, Folder 160)
  - Puerto Rico
    Puerto Rico
    - Puerto Rico, 1910-1914 (Reel M 07, Frame 18, Box 10, Folder 161)
    - Puerto Rico, 1910-1914 (Reel M 07, Frame 19, Box 10, Folder 162)
    - Puerto Rico, 1910-1914 (Reel M 07, Frame 20, Box 10, Folder 163)
  - Rhode Island
    Rhode Island
    - Rhode Island, 1910-1912 (Reel M 08, Frame 1, Box 10, Folder 164)
  - Samoa
    American Samoa
    - Samoa, 1910-1912 (Reel M 08, Frame 2, Box 10, Folder 165)
  - South Carolina
    South Carolina
    - South Carolina - General, 1910-1913 (Reel M 08, Frame 3, Box 10, Folder 166)
    - South Carolina - General, 1910-1913 (Reel M 08, Frame 4, Box 10, Folder 167)
    - South Carolina - General, 1910-1913 (Reel M 08, Frame 5, Box 10, Folder 168)
    - South Carolina - General, 1914-1915 (Reel M 08, Frame 6, Box 11, Folder 169)
    - South Carolina - Reports, 1911-1912, 1914 (Reel M 08, Frame 7, Box 11, Folder 170)
  - Tennessee
    Tennessee
    - Tennessee - General, 1910-1915 (Reel M 08, Frame 8, Box 11, Folder 171)
    - Tennessee - General, 1910-1915 (Reel M 08, Frame 9, Box 11, Folder 172)
    - Tennessee - General, 1910-1915 (Reel M 08, Frame 10, Box 11, Folder 173)
    - Tennessee - General, 1910-1915 (Reel M 08, Frame 11, Box 11, Folder 174)
    - Tennessee - General, 1910-1915 (Reel M 08, Frame 12, Box 11, Folder 175)
    - Tennessee - General, 1910-1915 (Reel M 08, Frame 13, Box 11, Folder 176)
    - Tennessee - General, 1910-1915 (Reel M 08, Frame 14, Box 11, Folder 177)
    - Tennessee - General, 1910-1915 (Reel M 08, Frame 15, Box 11, Folder 178)
    - Tennessee - Reports, 1910-1915 (Reel M 08, Frame 16, Box 11, Folder 179)
  - Texas
    Texas
    - Texas - General, 1909-1915 (Reel M 09, Frame 1, Box 12, Folder 180)
    - Texas - General, 1909-1915 (Reel M 09, Frame 2, Box 12, Folder 181)
    - Texas - General, 1909-1915 (Reel M 09, Frame 3, Box 12, Folder 182)
    - Texas - General, 1909-1915 (Reel M 09, Frame 4, Box 12, Folder 183)
    - Texas - Reports, 1912-1914 (Reel M 09, Frame 5, Box 12, Folder 184)
  - Virginia
    Virginia
    - Virginia - General, 1910-1911 (Reel M 09, Frame 6, Box 12, Folder 185)
    - Virginia - General, 1910-1911 (Reel M 09, Frame 7, Box 12, Folder 186)
    - Virginia - General, 1910-1911 (Reel M 09, Frame 8, Box 12, Folder 187)
    - Virginia - General, 1912-1915 (Reel M 09, Frame 9, Box 13, Folder 188)
    - Virginia - General, 1912-1915 (Reel M 09, Frame 10, Box 13, Folder 189)
    - Virginia - General, 1912-1915 (Reel M 09, Frame 11, Box 13, Folder 190)
    - Virginia - Reports, 1910-1914 (Reel M 09, Frame 12, Box 13, Folder 191)
  - West Virginia
    West Virginia
    - West Virginia, 1911-1914 (Reel M 09, Frame 13, Box 13, Folder 192)
- Minutes and Reports, 1909-1914; 3; 1.17 Cubic Feet 2 microfilm boxes (35mm) and 3 letter document boxes
  This series contains various Commission minutes, reports, and publications.
  - Bylaws, undated (Reel M 10, Frame 1, Box 13, Folder 193)
  - Minutes, 1909-1914 (Reel M 10, Frame 2, Box 13, Folder 194)
  - Minutes, 1909-1914 (Reel M 10, Frame 3, Box 13, Folder 195)
  - Minutes, 1909-1914 (Reel M 10, Frame 4, Box 13, Folder 196)
  - Minutes, 1909-1914 (Reel M 10, Frame 5, Box 13, Folder 197)
  - Minutes, 1909-1914 (Reel M 10, Frame 6, Box 13, Folder 198)
  - Minutes (Transcription), 1909-1914 (Reel M 10, Frame 7, Box 13, Folder 199)
  - Minutes (Transcription), 1909-1914 (Reel M 10, Frame 8, Box 13, Folder 200)
  - Minutes (Transcription), 1909-1914 (Box 14, Folder 201)
    Scope and Contents
    Because it consists of duplicate copies, this folder was not microfilmed.
    Existence and Location of Copies
    Copies of these transcribed Minutes are found in Box 13, Folders 199-200, which have been reproduced on microfilm reel 10.
  - Publications Nos. 1-9, 1910-1914 (Reel M 10, Frame 10, Box 14, Folder 202)
  - Publications Nos. 1, 4; Second Annual Report (Duplicates) (Box 14, Folder 203)
    Copies of these publications and reports are found in Box 14, Folder 202, which has been reproduced on microfilm reel 10.
  - Quarterly Report, Quarter Ending March 31, 1910 (Reel M 11, Frame 1, Box 15, Folder 204)
  - Quarterly Reports, June 1910-December 1914 (Reel M 11, Frame 2, Box 15, Folder 205)
- Financial Records, 1909-1915; 4; 1.9 Cubic Feet 1 microfilm box (35mm) and 3 oversize boxes
  This series consists of a ledger, a journal, and a cash book.
  - Cash Book, 1909-1915 (Reel M 11, Frame 3, Box 16, Folder 206)
  - Journal, 1910-1915 (Reel M 11, Frame 4, Box 17, Folder 207)
  - Ledger, 1910-1915 (Reel M 11, Frame 5, Box 18, Folder 208)
- Rockefeller Sanitary Commission Annual Reports, 1910-1914; 5; 5 Bound Volumes
  Arrangement
  Chronological
  Related Materials